RESUME

Personal Information

Name: Michael Sun Cell phone: (760)-833-0056 E-mail: sunla03@gmail.com

U.S. Green Card holder

Profile

10+ years of working experience in software development sector 10+ years in storage industry plus hands-on experiences on test automation using Python/KSH 3 years of hands-on coding web apps on both frontend an backend (javascript/python) Extensive experiences on UNIX/Linux platforms. Oracle OCP DBA, Microsoft MCDBA, and MCSE+I Rich experience working with global teams and strong at building and growing teams Self motivated. Work smart with strong execution, keep curious and learn quickly

Work Experience

2017-04 - 2019-10 Lead Software Engineer, Beijing Laimeet Technology Co., Itd

As the technical lead and architect, built the whole structure for both frontend and backend Coded frontend of our social network web app well as well guided the engineers on backend System tech stacks: H5/Javascript/Vue vs Nginx vs Python/Django/Rest vs PostgreSQL Mobile features: PWA, F7, Cordova as well as SPA/Webpack, Gitlab as code repository MVP(Minimum Viable Product) was released in one month Prototyped e-commerce/social app using H5/JQuery/Bootstrap/Django/Python/PostgreSQL Explored the Microservices architecture using javascript/Vue + java/spring

2011-09 - 2017-03 Senior Manager, Software Development, Oracle

Fully responsible for automation test on Oracle Solaris as well as ZFS Storage Appliance Develop automation test suites in KSH, Python and Selenium Webdriver Successful led the transformation from Ksh based development to Python Initiated, prototyped and successfully delivered the first BUI automation test suite, which shortened the test cycle from weeks to hours Successfully led the team to transform from waterfall development model to Agile model Grown the team from 6 to 30+ in size, including one manager and three team leads

2009-07 - 2011-08 Lead Software Engineer, Beijing TahooTech Co., ltd

Acted as SE to provide software solutions and IT services for manufacturing industry Reached out 100+ enterprise customers and completed 20+ demo and presentations to potential customers across 7 provinces

Provided onsite support on software installation, troubleshooting and upgrades

Used VC++ to customize the product upon customer's needs

2006-10 - 2009-07 Principal SQA Engineer, Symantec (Veritas)

Led the integration team to test Veritas NetBackup, SF and Symantec security products. Built the first website for project management throughout global integrations teams Successfully transformed the team from waterfall model to agile model Worked globally with program manager, developer manager, QA manager Acted as the key member of strategic planning committee of China Development Center

2003-02 - 2006-10 Senior Quality Assurance Engineer, CA Technologies

Led database and device QE team testing on CA storage product, ARCServe Provided TOI on databases (Oracle/DB2/Sybase/Informix/Ingres) to new hires Proposed and Successfully implemented Real World testing, greatly improved the product quality First engineer who began database testing and built the database team

2001-11 - 2002-12 Software Engineer, IBM China Development Lab

Tested IBM e-business solution Websphere Commerce Suite on UNIX and Linux platforms Developed automation build scripts using Shell First engineer who completed WCS cluster system verification as well as the guide revision Technical support on Oracle and DB2 databases

1996-03 - 2001-11 Software Engineer, Radar Institute

Developed client/server software using C/C++ on UNIX(RS/6000) and Windows Developed online OA website using ASP Developed identity system with QR code using VC++ Developed GP-IB software for instrument control using VB Maintained the legacy software system (Pascal) running on the DEC UNIX.

Education

Fordham University / Peking University, MBA
National University of Defense Technology, Bachelor, ElectroMechanical

Michael Sun

- Las Vegas, NV, USA
- New York, NY, USA

Contact Information

- sunla03@gmail.com (Preferred)
- mikesun2000@gmail.com
- michael.sun@ca.com
- laiqi.sun@gmail.com
- michael.sun@oracle.com
- michael.sun@blackstone.com
- michael.sun@mountsinai.org
- 7608330056 (Preferred)

Summary

at Mount Sinai Hospital

Work History

Total Work Experience: 23 years

- Lead Software Engineer | Beijing Laimeet Technology Co Apr 01, 2017 - Oct 01, 2019
- Senior Manager, Software Development | Oracle Corporation Sep 01, 2011 - Mar 01, 2017
- Lead Software Engineer | Beijing TahooTech Co
 Jul 01, 2009 Aug 01, 2011
- Principal SQA Engineer | Symantec
 Oct 01, 2006 Jul 01, 2009

Senior Quality Assurance Engineer | CA Technologies

Feb 01, 2003 - Oct 01, 2006

Software Engineer | IBM China Development Lab

Nov 01, 2001 - Dec 01, 2002

• Software Engineer | Radar Institute

Mar 01, 1996 - Nov 01, 2001

Education

- MBA, No Dates Provided | Fordham University / Peking University
- Bachelors, No Dates Provided | National University of Defense Technology

Skills

- software engineering | 11yrs | 2019
- software development | 10yrs | 2019
- software | 10yrs | 2019
- python | 8yrs | 2019
- engineering | 7yrs | 2019
- database | 6yrs | 2019
- git | 5yrs | 2019
- api | 3yrs | 2019
- html5 | 3yrs | 2019
- javascript | 3yrs | 2019
- web development | 3yrs | 2019
- qa | 12yrs | 2017
- storage | 12yrs | 2017
- test cases | 11yrs | 2017
- oracle | 10yrs | 2017
- **unix** | 10yrs | 2017
- acceptance testing | 9yrs | 2017
- scripting | 9yrs | 2017
- solaris | 9yrs | 2017
- framework | 9yrs | 2017
- test plans | 9yrs | 2017
- project management | 8yrs | 2017

- agile | 8yrs | 2017
- regression testing | 8yrs | 2017
- automated testing | 8yrs | 2017
- qa management | 8yrs | 2017
- sdet | 8yrs | 2017
- waterfall | 8yrs | 2017
- automation | 7yrs | 2017
- jira | 6yrs | 2017
- **nfs** | 6yrs | 2017
- **fc** | 6yrs | 2017
- selenium webdriver | 6yrs | 2017
- senior management | 6yrs | 2017
- staas | 6yrs | 2017
- transformation | 6yrs | 2017
- **selenium** | 3yrs | 2017
- **sql** | 5yrs | 2012
- vc | 8yrs | 2011
- programming | 6yrs | 2011
- **c++** | 6yrs | 2001
- client/server | 6yrs | 2001
- legacy systems | 6yrs | 2001
- visual basic | 6yrs | 2001
- asp | 1yrs | 2001
- hp loadrunner | 1yrs | 2001
- management
- active directory
- business continuity
- cloud computing
- data center
- disaster recovery
- enterprise architecture
- hp
- · information technology
- integration
- it management
- it operations
- it service management
- it strategy
- itil
- loadrunner
- · microsoft exchange
- network security
- process improvement
- security
- servers

- sharepoint
- virtualization
- vmware
- webdriver
- windows server
- alternative investments
- ethical hacker
- fund of funds
- information security

Work Preferences

- Likely to Switch: Most Likely
- Willing to Relocate: Yes
- Preferred Location:
 - o Seattle, WA, USA
 - o San Francisco, CA, USA
 - o Los Angeles, CA, USA
- Work Authorization:
 - o US
- Work Documents:
 - o Green Card
- Desired Hourly Rate: 50+ (USD)
- Desired Salary: 100000+ (USD)
- Security Clearance: No
- Third Party: No
- Employment Type:
 - o Full-time

Profile Sources

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-sun-5502aa6
- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/sunlaiqi